<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
  Flying Cat Hot Air Balloon model for FlightGear  
  Copyright (C) Herbert Wagner 2016
  This file is licensed under the GPL license
-->
<PropertyList>

 <!-- Specific keys -->
 <title>Hot Air Balloon Serie by HerbyW 2016-2018 Version 3.2 / Globos de Aire Caliente</title>
 <key>
  <name>q</name>
  <desc>Step 1: Initialize everything, wait till balloon has the same temperatur as outside</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>W</name>
  <desc>Step 2: Filling Hot Air to -3% for take off</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>D</name>
  <desc>Blower On, use after declining to fill in the air-cell to maximal value</desc>
 </key> 
 <key>
  <name>d</name>
  <desc>Blower Out</desc>
 </key> 
 <key>
  <name>g</name>
  <desc>Ballast dropping</desc>
 </key> 
 <key>
  <name>w</name>
  <desc>Show current on-ground weight.</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>F</name>
  <desc>Open Parachute valve.</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>f</name>
  <desc>Close Parachute valve.</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>R</name>
  <desc>Rip envelope.</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>E</name>
  <desc>Anchor</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>e</name>
  <desc>Turn Valve left</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>r</name>
  <desc>Turn Valve right</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>y</name>
  <desc>Change Model View and Panel View</desc>
 </key>
 <!-- Handling instructions. -->
 <text>
Panel Manual for Hot Air Balloon Serie by HerbyW
 
Preparing for Take-off
 
Open HUD "h", you see a lot of values.
Make the wind settings or metar data activ (see details below).
Press 1. Temp or "q": we get now all temperatures to the outside temperatur and get the balloon empty on ground.
Now press 2. HotAir, blows the air-cell to some level. Wait! (you may make a hot-fill with one burner)
(The HUD shows you the filling values, also the volume-meter)
Wait for the balloon to get filled, if you mess it up you will get strange weight issues. 
Wait till the balloon is filled and in a standing position!
Press 3.TakeOff or "W" to set the Hot Air cell to start conditions, press it again till the volume meter shows 100%.
In the payload menue you may set your guests weight up to 4 persons.

Take off

Start the burner with the switches on the panel, be aware that the burner-system has 1000 horse powers!
After a few minutes the balloon will start to lift 2-5 m, the fixed holding lines will be still activ.
Shut down the burner! Last change to get everything on board and check your systems.

Now you may loose the fixed lines and start your flight. (Pressing "E").

In flight

Ballast dropping ("g") OR fire on or out will get you to the desired height.
Descending: Parachute-valve ("F" on "f" out), watch Volume-Meters!
Use the blower "D" on, "d" out, to fill the air-cell after descending, and make the burner more effectiv.
Your flight direction is the white arrow in the compass,
adjust the airplane symbol by using the turn-valves "e" left, "r" right
or the Autopilot switch on the right bottom "Orientation Drift Controller".
Parachute Controller and Descending Controller you may set activ to controll
the maximum vertical speed of 3 m/s (more will get you into unstable flight).
The extra altitude hold switch should be activated if in horizontal flight,
then it will hold your altitude, on the right top of the panel. 

Befor Landing

Set anchor "E", it will get you down if in contact with the ground.

Ater touch down

Open the Rip-valve "R", watch animation.

You may make a new flight, just start from the top again.
 
Maximal altitude 13200 m (ca 43000 ft)
Maximal speed with jet-streams: +300 km/h

The consumption of propane for the burners is now implemented and allows you a 6 hours flight in normal altitude.

There is a extra meter for the cell-temperature in the blue box, it will shut down the burners if overheated.

Tip's and tricks
Sometimes the balloon start with a vertical speed of 30 m/s, if it happens just wait till it comes down
and start normal, or use a different starting position.

Change windspeed to change speed of the balloon:

Weather Conditions: Fair weather -- detailed weather -- advanced settings
Advanced weather Configuration: realistic weather, no terrain presampling!, Wind settings - Wind model: aloft interpol -- Wind Configuration

300/3  20/45  90/80  150/115  210/150  270/175  290/250  270/250 260/250

Flightlevel, Flightdirection

  500	=   170 Grad
1000	=   185 Grad
1500	=   190 Grad
2000	=   194 Grad
2500	=   196 Grad
3000	=   197 Grad
3500	=   198 Grad
4000	=   198 Grad
4500	=   200 Grad
5000	=   200 Grad
5500	=   210 Grad
6000	=   220 Grad
6500	=   230 Grad
7000	=   238 Grad

This setting illuminates a heavy jetsream to the east, so that everyone can make the same flight conditions
and a lot of differnt tasks may be done! FL00 is sea-level! Have fun!

Most information is from Cameron Balloons (UK), for more vist the webpage and get the manual for Hot-Air-Ballooning!
This version for Flightgear is handling most of it to get you the most realistic fun out of it.
Copyright by Herbert Wagner 09-2016.

############################################################################################################################
 
Manual del panel para globos de aire caliente de HerbyW 2016-2018
 
PREPARACION DEL DESPEGUE
 
Abre el HUD "h", veras muchos valores.
Realiza los ajustes de viento y los datos METAR activos (ver detalles abajo) *** ****



Presiona 1. TEMP o "q": obtenemos ahora todas las temperaturas del exterior y el globo vacio en la tierra.

Ahora presiona 2. HOTAIR (aire caliente), y ! espera ¡ 

(puedes hacer Hot-fill (relleno caliente) con un solo quemador)
(El HUD te muestra los valores de relleno, tambien la medida del volumen)

Espera a que el globo se llene, sino lo haces lo liaras, obteniendo problemas en el peso. 
! Espera hasta que el globo este relleno y en posicion de pie sostenido ¡


Presiona 3. TAKE-OFF (despegue) o "W" para configurar la celula de aire caliente en condicion de inicio), presionala de nuevo hasta
que el medidor de volumen muestre 100%
En el FGMENU --Carga y combustible--, podrias acondicionar el peso de tus invitados hasta 4 personas. 



DESPEGUE

Inicia el BURNER (quemador) con los interruptores del panel, ! estad advertidos ya que el sistema de quemadores tiene 1000 Cv de potencia ¡
Unos pocos minutos despues, el globo comenzara a ascender de 2-5m, las lineas de anclaje fijas aun estaran activas.
¡ Apaga el BURNER (quemador) ! Ultima oportunidad para poner todo a bordo y chequear los sistemas.

Ahora debes soltar las lineas de anclaje fijas y comenzar tu vuelo. (presionando "E").



EN VUELO

BALLAST DROPPING (lanzamiento de lastre) "g" y fuego encendido/apagado te llevaran a la altitud deseada.

El interruptor ALTITUD HOLD (mantener altitud) en la parte superior derecha del panel debe ser activado si se vuela en horizontal,
y entonces mantendra tu altitud



DESCENDER:

PARACHUTE-VALVE (valvula de paracaidas)  "F" ENCENDIDO "f" APAGADO, ¡ observa el medidor de volumen !
Usa BLOWER (soplador) "D" ENCENDIDO "d" APAGADO, para rellenar la celda de aire despues de descender,
y ser mas efectivo con el BURNER (quemador)
La indicacion de la direccion de tu vuelo es una flecha blanca en la brujula,
ajusta el simbolo del aeroplano usando las valvulas de giro L-TURN-R "e" izquierda,"r" derecha
o con el interruptor del autopiloto ORIENTATION DRIFT CONTROLLER (Controlador de la orientacion de deriva) situado abajo a la derecha 


Puedes activar PARACHUTE CONTROLER (controlador del paracaidas) y DESCENDING CONTROLLER (controlador del descenso) para controlar
la velocidad maxima vertical de 3m/s (con mas obtrendrias un vuelo inestable)



PREPARACION DEL ATERRIZAJE

ANCHOR (Anclas) Bajar anclas "E", te mantendran abajo si hacen contacto con el suelo.


DESPUES DE ATERRIZAR

Abrir RIP-VALVE (valvula de envoltura) "R", observa la animacion.


Si quieres hacer un nuevo vuelo, comienza estas instrucciones de nuevo.

 
Altitud maxima 13200 m (ca 43000 ft)
Maxima velocidad con corrientes de chorro: +300 km/h

El consumo de propano de los quemadores esta ahora implementado y te permite un vuelo de 6 horas en altitud normal.
En el cuadrante azul del panel hay un medidor extra que mide la temperatura de la celda CELL-TEMPERATURE, este apagaria
los quemadores si se sobrecalentaran


TRUCOS Y CONSEJOS
A veces el globo se inicia con una velocidad vertical de 30 m/s, si esto sucede espera un momento hasta que baje e inicia normalmente,
o usa otra posicion de salida.


***

Cambia la velocidad del viento para cambiar la velocidad del globo:
Ir a FGMENU -- WEATHER CONDITIONS: Seleccionar Fair Weather -- DETAILED WEATHER -- ADVANCED SETTINGS

AVANCED WEATHER CONFIGURATION: Realistic Weather, ¡ NO terrain presampling ! WIND SETTINGS - Wind Model: aloft interpol -- Wind Configuration

Rellenar los siguientes datos de direccion del viento-intensidad para crear un circuito virtual de viento interpolado en capas de altitud.

300/3  20/45  90/80  150/115  210/150  270/175  290/250  270/250 260/250

Esta configuracion imagina una corriente de chorro fuerte hacia el Este, de tal manera que todos pueden volar en la mismas condiciones
y un monton de otras tareas pueden ser realizadas. ! FL00 es el Nivel del Mar, Que os divertais !

***

La mayoria de la informacion es de Cameron Ballons (UK), para mas informacion visita la pagina web y  ¡ consigue el manual
de Globos de Aire Caliente !
Esta version para FlightGear maneja la mayor parte del manual con el mayor realismo y diversion.
Copyright Herbert Wagner 09-2016.
</text>


 <key>
  <name>q</name>
  <desc>Paso 1: Inizializa todo, espera hasta que el globo tenga la misma temperatura que el exterior.</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>W</name>
  <desc>Paso 2: Rellenar de aire caliente hasta -3% para el despegue</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>D</name>
  <desc>(Blower ON) Soplador encendido, usar despues de declinar hasta rellenar la celda de aire (air-cell) a su maximo valor</desc>
 </key> 
 <key>
  <name>d</name>
  <desc>(Blower Out) Soplador apagado</desc>
 </key> 
 <key>
  <name>g</name>
  <desc>Lanzar lastre</desc>
 </key> 
 <key>
  <name>w</name>
  <desc>Mostrar peso actual en tierra</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>F</name>
  <desc>Abrir la valvula del paracaidas</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>f</name>
  <desc>Cerrar la valvula del paracaidas</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>R</name>
  <desc>(Rip valve) Despegar la valvula de envoltura</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>E</name>
  <desc>Anclas</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>e</name>
  <desc>(L-Turn) Valvula de giro a izquierda</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>r</name>
  <desc>(R-Turn) Valvula de giro a derecha</desc>
 </key>
 <key>
  <name>y</name>
  <desc>Cambiar a vista de modelo y panel View</desc>
 </key>
 
</PropertyList>